<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pedro Alcàcer on Pedro Alcàcer - Lutenist</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/</link><description>Recent content in Pedro Alcàcer on Pedro Alcàcer - Lutenist</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/ensemble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/ensemble/</guid><description>Arlecchino innamorato A theatrical musical program bringing to life the commedia dell&amp;rsquo;arte character of Harlequin in love.
Ensemble Members:
Valentina Mastrangelo - Soprano Giampaolo Fagotto - Tenor (Arlecchino) Pedro Alcàcer Doria - Theorbo and Baroque Guitar Marco Mencoboni - Harpsichord and Musical Direction Les musiques du Roi Soleil Music from the court of Louis XIV, the Sun King, featuring the intimate sound of viols and theorbo.
Ensemble Members:
Juan Manuel Quintana - Viola da gamba Victor Aragón - Viola da gamba Pedro Alcàcer Doria - Theorbo</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/solo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/solo/</guid><description>Una storia fra le corde&amp;hellip; Vihuela and Theorbo
&amp;ldquo;A story among the strings&amp;rdquo; - this program weaves together narratives through the intimate sound of the vihuela and the resonant depths of the theorbo. Spanning from the Spanish Golden Age to the Italian Baroque, the program tells musical stories of love, devotion, and human experience.
Repertoire Themes Spanish Golden Age vihuela music Italian theorbo works Narrative and descriptive pieces Tanyer de gala Vihuela and Baroque Guitar</description></item><item><title>Anima Shirvani</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/anima-shirvani/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/anima-shirvani/</guid><description>See details and repertoire in the ensemble programme PDF (if available) or contact for booking.
Anima Shirvani is an ensemble program combining Renaissance textures with Eastern timbres.</description></item><item><title>Arlecchino innamorato</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/arlecchino-innamorato/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/arlecchino-innamorato/</guid><description>Theatrical ensemble programme centred on the character Arlecchino.</description></item><item><title>Bologna liutistica</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/bologna-liutistica/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/bologna-liutistica/</guid><description>Download the original program PDF: Download PDF
Bologna liutistica Renaissance lute and Theorbo
Lute 3 Fantasie — Francesco Canova da Milano (Intavolatura di Lauto, Venice 1546) Passacaglia — Alessandro Piccinini (Bologna 1623) O dulx Roveoir / Ballo Allemano — Giovanni Antonio Terzi (Intavolatura di liuto, Venice 1593) Theorbo / Chitarrone Arpeggiata Toccata prima Works by Giovanni Girolamo Kapsperger (Rome 1616) Aria di sarabanda Toccata in G minor Partite sopra quest&amp;rsquo;aria francese detta l&amp;rsquo;Alemana Toccata-corrente-gagliarda in G major (Piccinini) Notes Selected partite and dances from the Bologna tradition, featuring lute repertory and theorbo/chitarrone arrangements drawn from 16th–17th century sources.</description></item><item><title>Caravelle della musica</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/caravelle-della-musica/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/caravelle-della-musica/</guid><description>Ensemble programme blending Iberian and Italian repertoire for Renaissance consorts.</description></item><item><title>Dos peninsulas</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/dos-peninsulas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/dos-peninsulas/</guid><description>Dos peninsulas Renaissance lute and Baroque guitar
Lute (Renaissance) 5 Fantasie — Francesco Canova da Milano (Venezia 1546) Fantasía / Pavana de Alexandre / Romanesca — Alonso de Mudarra (Sevilla 1546) Toccata — Giovanni Girolamo Kapsperger (Rome 1616) Baroque Guitar Folias españolas e italianas Suite in A minor Preludio, Allemanda, Giga, Burlesca — Santiago de Murcia (ca. 1730) Pasacalle sobre la D — Gaspar Sanz (1674) Tarantella, Fandango, Canario Notes A dialogue between Iberian and Italian plucked-string traditions, pairing Renaissance lute works with baroque guitar repertoire.</description></item><item><title>Les musiques du Roi Soleil</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/les-musiques-du-roi-soleil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/les-musiques-du-roi-soleil/</guid><description>Programme featuring music from the court of Louis XIV for viols and theorbo.</description></item><item><title>Luis Milán — El Maestro</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/discs/luis-milan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/discs/luis-milan/</guid><description> Luis Milán: El Maestro Amazon Bandcamp Deezer Spotify Tidal Youtube YouTube playlist Tracklist - Track 1: ... - Track 2: ...</description></item><item><title>Tanyer de gala</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/tanyer-de-gala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/tanyer-de-gala/</guid><description>Download the original program PDF: Download PDF
Short description: Vihuela and baroque guitar.
Tanyer de gala Vihuela and Baroque guitar
Vihuela Ricercar 3 — Francesco da Milano (Intabulatura de lauto, Venice 1546) Fantasia para desenvolver las manos — Alonso de Mudarra (Sevilla 1546) Guardame las Vacas — Luis de Narváez (Los seis libros del Delfín, Valladolid 1538) Fantasia 7 — Luis de Narváez Pavana 4 — Luys Milán (El maestro, Valencia 1536) Baroque Guitar / Chitarra Preludio, Allemanda, Giga e Burlesca — Santiago de Murcia (Passacalles y obras, ca.</description></item><item><title>Tres territorios</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/tres-territorios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/tres-territorios/</guid><description>Download the original program PDF: Download PDF
Tres territorios Baroque guitar and Theorbo
Baroque Guitar Fandango — Santiago de Murcia (Codice Saldivar ca. 1730) Pavana por la D Pasacalle sobre la D — Gaspar Sanz (Instrucción para sonar la guitarra, Zaragoza 1674) Tarantella Folias Españolas — Santiago de Murcia Theorbo / Tiorba Arpeggiatta Works by Giovanni Girolamo Kapsberger (Kapsberger repertory) Toccata V Corrente Gagliarda Toccata VIII Partite su l’Alemana / Partite su la Romanesca — Alessandro Piccinini Notes Program mixes Iberian guitar dance forms and Italian theorbo repertoire, showcasing stylistic contrasts and historical sources.</description></item><item><title>Una storia fra le corde...</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/una-storia-fra-le-corde/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/una-storia-fra-le-corde/</guid><description>Download the original program PDF: Download PDF
Short description: Vihuela and theorbo.
Una storia fra le corde&amp;hellip; Vihuela and Theorbo
Vihuela Fantasia para desenvolver las manos — Alonso de Mudarra (Tres libros de música en cifras para Vihuela, Sevilla 1546) Fantasia del quarto tono Mille Regez — Luis de Narváez (Los seis libros del Delfín, Valladolid 1538) Pavana 4 — Luys Milán (El maestro, Valencia 1536) Romanesca — Alonso de Mudarra (Tres libros de música en cifras para Vihuela, Sevilla 1546) Fantasía I (4th Book) Benedictus — Josquin Soneto lombardo — Enrriquez de Valderrábano (Silva de sirenas, Valladolid 1547) Bassa de contrapunto Chitarrone / Theorbo Toccata-corrente-gagliarda in G major — Alessandro Piccinini (Libro di intavolatura di Liuto et di chitarrone, Bologna 1623) Toccata in G minor Partite sopra quest&amp;rsquo;aria francese detta l&amp;rsquo;Alemana Notes Program emphasises Iberian vihuela repertoire alongside theorbo works drawn from Italian sources, forming a narrative journey through the strings.</description></item><item><title>Viaggio musicale nell'Emilia del 600'</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/viaggio-musicale-emilia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/viaggio-musicale-emilia/</guid><description>Ensemble programme featuring instrumental works from 17th-century Emilia.</description></item><item><title>Volcania</title><link>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/volcania/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pedroalcacer.com/en/programs/volcania/</guid><description>Chamber music programme directed by leading early music specialists.</description></item></channel></rss>